<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Snort on Kaleb Neeble</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/snort/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Snort on Kaleb Neeble</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 23:51:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/snort/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Snort IDS Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/projected/projects2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 23:51:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/projected/projects2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-secure-intrusion-detection-system&#34;&gt;Creating Secure Intrusion Detection System&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of my recent projects is a &lt;strong&gt;Instrusion Detection System&lt;/strong&gt;, designed using pcap files. This project is used to demonstrate the various different details of attacks would look like on intrusion detection systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-it-does&#34;&gt;What It Does&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The system is used to analyze various TCP ports, detect malformed packets, payloads, and uses custom snort rules to authenicate events/flag.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-features&#34;&gt;Key Features&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Port Scan Detection&lt;/strong&gt;: Analyzed TCP port scans, characterized traffic patterns, and created custom snort rules.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malformed Packet Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: Identified IP flooding and packet anomalies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malicious Payload Identification&lt;/strong&gt;: Used Wireshark to detect and analyze malicious payloads.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Snort Rules&lt;/strong&gt;: Developed rules for TFTP write requests and RADIUS authentication events.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How It Works&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are given capture files, which can be used to create your own custom snort rules in order to detect intrusions, as well as analyze in wireshark. Group 1 capture is used for port scanning to find packet anomalies. Group 2 is used as a capture to help demonstrate the appearance of malformed packets. Group 3 is used to detect malicious payloads through snort. Finally, Group 4 is used to create your own custom snort rules to detection instrusions into the system which can send alerts and detect anomalies/attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
